目覚めては繰り返す
Day after day, I awake in a daze,
mezamete ha kurikaesu nemui asa ha
目覚めては繰り返す　眠い朝は
眠い朝は
襟のタイをきつく締め
And fasten my collar tightly.
eri no tai wo kitsuku shime
襟のタイをきつく締め
教室のドアくぐると
As I walk through the door to my classroom,
kyoushitsu no doa kuguru to hon no sukoshi
教室のドアくぐるとほんの少し
ほんの少し胸を張って歩き出せる
I have the slightest bit of pride.
mune wo hatte arukidaseru
胸を張って歩き出せる
Then a wind rushed through that normal, everyday life.
sonna nichijou ni fukinukeru kaze
そんな日常に吹き抜ける風
そんな日常に
吹き抜ける風
聞こえた気がした　感じた気がしたんだ
I have a feeling I can hear it,
kikoeta ki ga shita
聞こえた気がした
I have a feeling I can sense it,
kanjita ki ga shitanda
感じた気がしたんだ
震えだす 今この胸で
Beginning to tremble within my chest.
furuedasu ima kono mune de
震え出す今この胸で
I have a feeling it's on its way,
mou kuru ki ga shita
もう来る気がした
As the millions of stars began to disappear,
ikuoku no hoshi ga kiesatteku no wo
幾億の星が消え去ってくのを
I sent them on their way,
miokutta
見送った
見送った 手を振った
Waving my hand,
te wo futta
手を振った
良かったねと
Whispering, "Congratulations".
yokatta ne, to
よかったね、と
んぅ　時間か
It's time.
待ち合わせ場所に行かないと
I'd better go get her.
さて、次は誰にすっかな
Now, who should we work on next?
奏の意見も聞いて見るか
Courtyard
Classroom Building
Maybe I'll ask Kanade what she thinks.
Hey.
あっ　日向
Hinata!
Otonashi-san.
音無さん
直井
Naoi!
うぉ　こっ　お前ここで何してんだよ
What are you doing here?!
And where did you come from?
貴様こそどこから湧いて出た
So... did the two of you need something?
ああー　で　ふたりとも何か用なのか
直井：おお　そうだ　どこに行こうとしてたんだよ　音無
日向：あっそうだ　どこに行くんですか　音無さん
Ah, yes. Where were you headed, Otonashi-san?
Ah, yeah. Where were you going, Otonashi?
どこだっていいだろ
It's none of your business!
It's none of your business.
貴様には関係ない
I've got business with Otonashi!
オレは音無に用があるんだ
あいつのやろうとしてることを手伝うためにな！
I'm here to help him accomplish something!
ふん　それこそ僕の仕事
But that would be my role.
貴様は邪魔だ
You're not necessary.
Get lost.
とっとと消えろ
Good. Look into my eyes.
さぁ　僕の目を見るんだ
貴様はトイレットペーパーだ
You're a roll of toilet paper.
あっという間に流されていくトイレットペーパーの潔さに気づっ
Realise how swiftly toilet paper is washed away.
Hey, now, cut it out!
こらこら　やめろ
H-Hey, Hinata!
おいおい　日向
僕がお手伝いさせていただきます
Please allow me to assist you.
Do you guys even know what I'm trying to do?
って　お前ら　オレのやろうとしてることがわかってんのか
Of course.
わかってるよ
Of course I do.
わかってますとも
一人ずつ消していくんでしょ？
You're trying to erase us one by one, right?
Coming from you, it sounds more like a crime.
お前が言うと犯罪行為に聞こえるな
If you think about it, Naoi,
you don't have any regrets now.
そもそも直井　お前はもう思い残すことがないはずなんじゃないのか
僕はあなたと一緒にいたいんです
I want to be with you. Besides...
それにこいつより先に消えたくありません
...I don't want to disappear before him.
Don't stay behind for a reason like that.
そんな理由で残るなっての
じゃ どうしたらいいんですか
Then what am I supposed to do?
Disappear.
消えるんだよ
Nobody asked you.
貴様には訊いてない
ねぇ音無さん　パートナーが必要でしょ
Say, Otonashi-san, you need a partner, right?
Please use me, Otonashi-san.
僕を使いこなしてくださいよ 音無さん
ん？どうかしましたか
Is something the matter?
お前っ 何だ…また何かしたのか？
What is this? Did you do something again?!
What are you talking about?
何のことだ　僕は何も…
I haven't done-
何だよこれ！敵か！？
What the hell's this?
Is it an enemy? Can we shoot it?
撃っていいのか！？
It's invading...
入ってくる　何か入ってきます
Something's invading me, Otonashi-san!
音無さん！
Damn it!
クッソー
Hinata!
日向！
Can this thing die?
死ぬのかよ　これ
やったのか
Did we kill it?
What was that?
なんだったんだよ
日向さん 音無さん２名で迎撃
Target intercepted by Hinata-san and Otonashi-san.
撃破
It's been exterminated. No casualties.
全員無事です
A second one showed up, huh?
二体目の出現か
Anti-Tenshi Operation HQ
It'd be natural to assume it's one of Tenshi's new skills, but...
天使の新たなるスキルと考えるのが一番自然だけど
しっくりきませんか
That doesn't sound right to you?
そうね
No, it doesn't.
This is an edict to all Battlefront members:
戦線メンバー総員に通達
No one is permitted to travel alone.
今後は単独行動を禁止
最低でも二人一組で行動
Move together with a minimum of one other person at all times.
カゲを天使とは別の敵勢勢力として対処する
The Shadows will be considered an enemy unrelated to Tenshi.
Be sure to maintain high alert.
警戒態勢を常に厳とするように
了解です
Roger.
ゆりっぺさんは
And you, Yurippe-san?
"Yurippe-san" is going to eliminate some possibilities.
ゆりっぺさんは考えうる可能性を潰しておくわ
Student Council President, Tachibana Kanade-san.
生徒会長のタチバナ奏さん　いますぐ生徒会室まで来てください
繰り返します　生徒会長のタチバナ奏さんいますぐ生徒会室まで来てください
Incinerator
Please report to the Student Council room immediately.
なあ　これゆりっぺの声じゃん
Hey, that's Yurippe, isn't it?
I repeat.
What is this about?
どういう事だ
Student Council President, Tachibana Kanade-san.
Crap. She might hear from her what we're trying to do.
やっベー　俺たちのやろうとしてることがバレるかもしれねー
Please report to the Student Council room immediately.
そりゃまずい
That can't be good.
行こう
Let's go!
You got it.
ああ
Student Council Room
何よ　あんたたち
What are you guys doing?
Student Council Room
傍聴さしてくれ
Let us listen.
元生徒会長代理
I, as the ex-deputy president and
current vice president, permit them.
現副会長の僕が許可しました
Why is this under your jurisdiction?
何であんたの管轄なのよ
生徒会室ですから
This is the Student Council room.
Fine.
まあ　いいわ
で　どうなの
So? What are these shadows?
カゲよ　カゲ
知らない
I don't know.
あなたがプログラミングしたんじゃないの
You didn't program them?
違う
I did not.
Then it could be a bug.
じゃあバグという可能性があるわ
最近プログラミングしたのはいつ
When was the last time you did any programming?
The day before yesterday.
一昨日
Timing-wise, it's a perfect match.
タイミング的にはドンピシャね
部屋に入らせてもらうけど いい？
I'll be sending people into your room, understand?
Takeyama-kun, it's your show.
竹山君 よろしく
了解
Roger.
あとクライスっ
And call me Chr-
So, what sort of program did you write?
で どんなプログラムを？
Wings.
羽
羽？
"Wings"? You added wings?
羽をつけたの？
So you can fly?
まさか飛べるように？
No. They're for decoration.
ううん
飾り
えっ　飾り？
"Decoration"?
Yes. Decoration.
そう　飾り
Why?
何で？
Because I was told that I would look more like an angel that way.
その方が天使らしいからだって
"Told"? Who told you that?
だって
誰に言われたの？
Crap...
あっ　マズイ
That would be me.
それは僕です
生徒会長としての箔がつくかと思い
I felt it would add to her supremacy as president, so I,
元生徒会長代理
現副会長の僕がそう提言しました
the ex-deputy president and
current vice president, suggested it to her.
A president with wings looks supreme, you say?
生徒会長に羽が生えたら箔がつくの？
Yes.
はい　生徒会長に 羽 相応しいかと
Wings for the president.
I believe it's fitting.
アホだ
What a dumbass.
しかし 意外に従順ね
By the way, you're being pretty obedient.
冷酷さなんて微塵も感じられない
You don't seem heartless at all.
以前と変わらないように見えるわ
No different from how you were before.
No, she is heartless.
いえ 冷酷です
As the vice president, I get stabbed by her each day.
副会長の僕が 毎日刺されています
Um, why?
えっ どうして？
機嫌が悪いと会長は近くにあるものを刺すんです
When she's in a bad mood, she stabs anything near her.
副会長という立場上割と近くにいることが多いので
As the vice president, I'm often nearby, so as a result, I'm stabbed often.
よく刺されます
今朝も刺されてしばらく腸がはみ出したままでした
I was stabbed this morning, actually,
and my intestines were hanging out for a while.
今はとても…機嫌がいいようですが
But right now, she seems to be in a good mood.
アホだ
What a dumbass.
聞こえますか
Do you copy? Please respond.
応答してください
竹山くんね　どうだった
How is it, Takeyama-kun?
Tenshi's Domain
Girls' Dormitory
バグは見つかりませんでした
I couldn't find any bugs.
特に今回のプログラムは
Besides, this program is for decoration only, so it's a relatively simple one.
装飾付けという比較的単純なものです
意志を持って人を襲うようなバグなど発生しようがありません
It couldn't possibly produce a bug with a mind of its own that attacks people.
あと 僕のことはクライスッ
Also, please call me Chr-
What about the other programs?
他のプログラムは？
パッシブに「オーバードライブ」
There's Overdrive in passive mode. Hand Sonic in active mode.
アクティブに「ハンドソニック」
以前と同じものです
All of them are just the same as before. Although their forms look different.
形状は違いますけど
What would you like to do?
どうしますか？
消させる気か
Is she going to make him delete it?
She'd have to rewrite it from scratch.
また一から作りなおしになる
おい　今銃声が聞こえなかったか
Hey, did you just hear that gunshot?
何言ってるの　銃声なんか
What gunshot? I didn't hear any-
そとだ
It's coming from outside!
見ろ　あそこだ
Look! Over there!
It's those monsters!
あの怪物
なんだよ　あの数
My God! Look at how many of them...
Kanade! Please!
奏 頼む
ああ　ゆりっぺ
Yurippe!
Wow...
すげえ
I'm going, too!
俺も行くぜ
H-Hey!
あ　おい
音無さん
Otonashi-san!
大丈夫か　ゆり
Are you okay, Yuri?
Otonashi-kun.
音無くん
Sorry for the wait!
待たせたな
ふん　ひれ伏せ
Hit the deck.
ふん　加勢などいらん
I don't need help!
へッ　まあそう言うなって
Don't be like that.
How unwise.
浅はかなり
Whoa! Dancing in the shadow!
I kiss you.
うわ　あれ食らいたくねー
I'd hate to get hit with that.
てめ 味方ごと斬る気かよ！
Are you trying to cut us down with them?!
計算の内だ
That's just part of my plan.
Take it out next time!
入れるなよ　省けよ！
Stop horsing around and support each other!
バカやってないで　援護しあって
That was...
あれは
みんな　無事か
Is everyone safe?
Yeah. What were they? Are they monsters?
ぬぅ　何なんだよ　あいつら　化け物かよ
あんな不気味な存在　この世界にはいなかったぞ
Those freaky creatures never existed in this world before.
これは悪夢か
Is this some sort of nightmare?
誘い乱れるcarnival
A carnival of nightmares.
Maybe we've been in this world for too long.
この世界に長くいすぎたのかしら
What do you mean?
どういう事だ
You've seen invincible monsters in games meant to prevent one from being able to play said game forever, right?
ゲームでよくあるじゃない
永久プレイ阻止のために出てくる無敵のモンスター
That's not funny at all.
笑えないな
にしても　まるで味方ね
At any rate,
she's acting as our ally.
Hey! Hey!
おい　おい
Fujimaki?
藤巻
やべぇぞ
We got a problem...
Takamatsu! Takamatsu lost!
高松が…
高松がやられちまったぁ！
Those are his glasses.
あいつのメガネだ
Classroom
Building
Connecting Corridor
ぼく見たんだ
I saw it. That shadow ate him.
あの影に食われるところを
"Ate"?
食われるって
僕が出くわした時にはもう
By the time I saw him, he was already completely covered by a Shadow.
全身影に覆われていて
僕も助けようとしたんだ
I tried to save him, too!
でも　どうしようもなくて
But I couldn't do anything.
最後にはメガネまで外れて
In the end, his glasses fell...
Who'd have thought he'd drop his glasses...
あいつがメガネを落とすなんて
How unreal. And then?
相当だぜ
で
地面に飲み込まれていた
He was sucked into the ground.
地面に？
"The ground"?
This is too much of an irregularity...
イレギュラーすぎる
なんだ
What's going on? A third party, that's not related to any of us, is starting to take action.
俺たちの思惑とは違う意識が働き初めてる
一体なにがおきているんだ
What exactly is going on?
高松がいたぞ
I found Takamatsu!
高松
Takamatsu-san!
Takamatsu!
Classroom
Classroom Building A
What's going on? Everyone was worried about you.
どういうつもりだ　みんな心配してたんだぞ
"Worried"? Over what?
心配？
何をですか？
"Over what"? You got eaten by that shadow monster!
何をって
お前　カゲの化けもんに食われたんだろう
何を言っているのか　分かりませんが
I don't really know what you could mean.
自分じゃ気づいてなかったのか
Maybe he doesn't realise what happened?
カゲにくわれたんだよ
You got eaten by a shadow!
で　地面に飲み込まれてたんだよ
And then you got sucked into the ground.
あれから　どうした
What did you do after that?
どうしてもなにも
What did I do?
いつものように寮で起きて学校に来ただけですが
I woke up at the dorm and came to school like I do any other day.
"Came to school"?
学校にくる！？
そっちの制服に着替えて授業を受けに来たってのか
You're here to attend class in that uniform?
Well, yes.
ええ　ま
You'll disappear! Don't you get that?!
消えるぞ！　わかってんのか！
"Disappear"?
消える？
何が消えるんですか？
What do you mean, "disappear"?
Holy crap. He's gone bonkers.
やべーぜこいつ
おかしくなってる
元からおかしい奴だったけどさぁ
Well, he was to begin with, but still...
高松
Takamatsu...
もう十分よ　日向くん
That's enough, Hinata-kun.
じゅうぶんって　なにが
Enough of what?
I'm sorry to say this, but you're interrupting class.
すみませんが　授業の邪魔です
出ましょう
Let's go.
イイのかよ　ほっといて
You sure we want to leave him?
消えちまうぞ
He'll disappear!
イイから
Just come.
Ooyama-kun!
大山君
His reactions just now speak volumes.
いまの問答だけでじゅうぶんよ
Stairs
Classroom Building A
なにが起きたか分かったわ
I've grasped what's happened to him.
彼　NPCになっちゃったのよ
He's turned into an NPC.
H-Hold on! What does that mean?!
ちょっ　ちょっと待ってよ　それってどういうことだよ
This is too hard.
わけ分かんねー
If he's an NPC, then he doesn't have a soul any more, right?
NPCってことは魂がないっていうこと？
Then, where did his soul go?
じゃ彼の魂はどこに行っちゃったの
それを食われちゃったんじゃない
Maybe that's what was eaten.
それってどういうことだよ
What's that supposed to mean?!
なに　あいつが消えることもできずに
You mean he's even lost the chance to disappear and has to take classes here forever?
永遠にああっやってここで授業を受け続けていくってことか
そういうことになるわ
That's right.
そんな
That's... That's even worse than dying.
それって死ぬよりかひどくねぇ？
So, really forever? He's locked in here forever?
永遠にかよ　永遠にここに閉じ込められちまったのかよ
なんだよ　そりゃ
What kinda sick joke is that?!
Damn it!
くそ
That's just screwed up...
ひでえ
こんなことが起こりうるのか　この世界は
So something like this is possible in this world.
これじゃ天使に消されちまったほうがまだマシじゃねえかよ
It'd be better gettin' erased by Tenshi.
Plus, it looks like the shadow is multiplying.
しかも　影は増殖をはじめているようだが
What do we need to do, Yurippe?
ねえ　どうすればイイの　ゆりっぺ
Gym
この世界に異変が起き始めている
Something strange is starting to happen in this world.
天使とは異なる敵の出現
To begin with, the appearance of enemies other than Tenshi.
まんまでなんだけど　影と呼んでる
For lack of originality, we call them "shadows".
Unlike Tenshi, they appear suddenly and attack us at random.
天使と違って神出鬼没で
無差別に攻撃を仕掛けてくる
カゲに喰われたものは　魂を失い
Once eaten by a shadow, you lose your soul and are turned into an NPC that attends class every day.
毎日授業を受けるNPCと化す
現在無制限で増殖中
Currently, they are multiplying without limit. The cause is unknown.
原因は不明　打開策もいまのところなし
We have no countermeasure at this time.
先に遊佐さんにつけてもらったように
As Yusa-san said earlier, you need to protect each other by staying in groups.
集団行動で身を守りあってもらうしかない
さて　こうした危機に瀕するなか
Now, in the midst of this crisis, we have people developing a different ideal within the Battlefront,
この「死んだ世界戦線」に別の思想を持つ者たちが現れ
and they are trying to lead the organisation in a new direction.
「戦線」を新たなる道に導こうとしてる
That direction could lead to a countermeasure to the crisis we're facing.
その道は
現在のこの世界における危機回避の一つの選択肢にもなりえる
So, as the representative of that faction, Otonashi-kun,
なので　そちらの代表として　音無君
could you share your ideal with all of us?
堂々とここでその思いを語ってもらえるかしら
ばれてましたね
She knew about us.
行けよ
Go on up.
Screw you!
巫山戯んな　いい加減なことをいうな
That's all baseless!
It couldn't be true!
そんな都合のイイ話があるか
そうだ　この世界にあってたまるか
Yeah! Nothing like that could exist here!
あったんだよ
Well it does.
Yui found it.
ユイはそれを見つけた
オレみたいな人間のくずのまま死んできたようなやつでもさ
Even I died as a worthless husk of a person.
この世界でそれを与えてやることができた
But in this world, I was able to give her purpose.
ボクもです
The same applies to me.
ボクは神ですが
I am God...
それでも　音無さんだけが僕に人のココロを取り戻させてくれた
But Otonashi-san managed to help me regain my human heart,
たった一言かけてくれた労いの言葉で
all with a single pat on the back.
It's entirely your choice which path you take.
どの道を選ぶかは　みんなに任せるわ
What about you? What will you do, Yurippe?
ゆりっぺは　ゆりっぺはどうするんだ
Me? I've always done what I want to.
アタシ
アタシはいつだって勝手だったし
アナタたちを守りゃあしないし
I can't protect you all, either.
アタシがしたいようにするだけよ
So I'll continue to do what I want.
We don't have much time.
あまり時間はないわ　各自よく考えておいて
All of you should consider it.
That's all. Dismissed!
以上　解散
ちょっとイイ
You have a moment?
What do you want, Yuri?
なんだ　ゆり
Make her work to intercept the shadows.
その子をカゲの迎撃にあたらせなさい
Kanade? Why?
奏を
なぜ
She's more suited for fighting without thought.
頭を使って行動させるより
なにも考えず戦わせるほうが向いてるわよ
At least, based on what I saw.
見てた分には
見られてたのかよ
So you were watching...
まっ　ゆりっぺの目は欺けんわな～
Man, we can't deceive Yurippe's eyes, can we?
But Kanade is on our side. She should stay with us!
でも　奏はオレたちの仲間だ
一緒にいるべきだ
ほかのメンバーだってアナタたちの仲間でしょう
So are all the other members.
To protect them, we need her strength.
彼らを守るには　その子のチカラが必要よ
我々戦線と長きに渡り戦ってきた
We need her great strength, which she used to fight against the Battlefront for so long.
その圧倒的なチカラがね
You're right. It's a fitting role for her as an angel.
たしかに　天使だけにそれが適任だな
She's not an angel, you know?
別にその子　天使じゃないわよ
Huh?! What did you just say?!
えっ　いまなんつった
I said she's not an angel.
その子　天使じゃないわよ
アタシたちと同じ人間よ
She's a human just like us.
気づいてなかったの
You never realised?
へえええっ
God is omniscient.
神がなんでも見通しでしたが
動揺してんじゃねーかよ
You're shaking.
Y-You're not an angel?
お前　天使じゃねーの
うん　アタシは天使なんかじゃない
"I'm not an angel."
I'm certain I said that to you when we first met.
それは初めて会ったときにそう答えているはずなんだけど
She was calling you an angel or whatnot.
「...あんたが天使だとかなんとか言って」
「アタシは天使なんかじゃないわ」
I'm not an angel.
がっほんとだ
She did!
いろいろあったからな～
Yeah, a lot's happened since, hasn't it?
お前らのせいだろ
This is all your fault!
じゃ　奏はなぜここにいる
In that case, why is Kanade here?!
生徒会長なんてしていて　なぜ消えなかった
Why didn't she disappear after becoming the student council president?
彼女なりのここにいる理由があるんでしょう
She must have her reasons for staying here.
あ　そっか
Right...
Then just like us, she has some kind of regret.
じゃ　俺たちと同じようになにかを抱えてきてんだな
そいつも解消してやらねえとな～
We'll need to take care of that, too.
Right?
なっ
So, Yuri... what will you do?
で　ゆり　お前はどうする
There's something I want to find out.
確かめてみたいことがあるの
Are you going to fight against the shadows?
戦うのか　影と
If it's necessary.
場合によっては
It's dangerous to go alone!
一人じゃ危険だ
だってしかたないじゃない
What can I do? I gave everyone the freedom to choose.
ほかのみんなには選ぶ自由を与えたんだから
お前に付いて行くやつもいるはずだ
I'm sure some will follow you.
考える時間は必要よ
They need time to think.
大事なことだもの
It's an important decision.
Yeah... it is, but...
そりゃ　そうだけど
If everyone's disappeared and has safely left this world by the time I return,
戻ってきたとき　みなが消えて
無事この世界から去っていたら
あなたのおかげだと　思っておくわ
then I'll believe you did what you had to do.
Stop that! I'll be waiting!
そんな
オレは待ってる
Don't be an idiot. If you wait alone, the shadows will get you.
バカね　一人で待ってじゃ影にやられちゃうわよ
そうなる前に　あなたもさっさと去りなさい
You should leave this world before that happens.
この世界から
アタシのことは気にしないで
Don't worry about me.
いや　気にするよ
No, we will worry.
日向君
Hinata-kun...
いきなりなに言ってんだよ
What are you saying all of a sudden?
二人から始まった「戦線」じゃねーか
This Battlefront started with just us two.
長い時間一緒に過ごしてきたよな
We spent lots of time together, didn't we?
So we'll end it together.
だから　終わるときも一緒だ
I won't leave without you.
オレはお前を置いて行かない
You're such an idiot, as always.
相変わらず　あなたバカね
Sentiment won't solve a thing.
感情論じゃ何も解決しないわよ
敵襲　敵襲だ
Enemy! Enemy raid!
奏ちゃん　よろしく
Kanade-chan, please go.
「ハンドソニック」　バージョン５
Hand Sonic: Version 5.
Well, we'll meet again if we can.
じゃ　また会えたら会いましょう
Yurippe!
ゆりっぺ
What a terrible nickname.
ひどいあだ名
でも　そのおかげでみんなに慕われたのかもね
But... maybe that's why people flocked to me.
Thank you.
ありがとう
いつも一人で歩いてた
振り返るとみんなは遠く
●
それでも私は歩いたそれが強さだった
．
●
もう何も 怖くない
そうつぶやいてみせる
いつか　人は一人になって
．
思い出の中に生きてくだけ
孤独さえ愛し笑ってられるように
．
私は戦うんだ
涙なんて見せないんだ
Okay.
よし　もうここまでにしておこう
Christ of the Front's Journal
I'll stop it here.
It's another sunny day
It seems I've been in this world too long
I've come to change how I think
I'll say it again
It's another sunny day
Starting tomorrow
I should be able to see an even clearer sky
あの変容
That transformation.
あの子と同じように
Just like that boy, if an NPC's programming can be rewritten...
もしNPCもプログラミングにより書き換えが可能だとすれば
That means there's a person using that software to change NPCs into shadows, setting them to attack us.
あのソフトを使って　NPCをカゲに変えて
あたしたちを襲う
そんな神様気取りのふざけた真似をしているやつがいま
There's someone playing God for this world and using this to screw around with us.
この世界のどこかにいるってことに
Wherever this person is, there must also be countless computers.
そこにはコンピュータが何台もあるはず
とすれば　場所は一つしかない
And if so, there's only one possible place.
Library
Computer Room 1
1st PC Room
Inside the Library
チェックメイト
Checkmate.
Raise your hands in the air.
手を上げなさい
うん　なにがじゃ
Hm? What's this now?
チェックメイトとな　チェスでもやったんだか
"Checkmate"?
Were you playing chess?
He's the one behind all this?
この人が犯人？
もうなんでもパソコンの時代
The world requires computers for everything.
アナログのゲームもまた一興
Playing an analogue game is good too, though.
Despite being young, you have a good hobby.
あんた若いのに　よい趣味をお持ちじゃ
Wait right there!
待ちなさい
うん　ワシか
Me?
What were you doing?
なにをしていた
ここでか
Here?
Yes.
そう
I was setting up a new computer.
新しいコンピュータの設置じゃが
なんのために
For what reason?
高価のせいか　よく盗まれる
Maybe it's because computers are valuable, but they often get stolen.
足りなくなったら　補充せねばならん
If they go missing, I need to replace them.
Do you have any idea who takes them?
犯人の目星は
いまのところはなんとも
Not at the moment.
もうイイかな
May I go now?
ありがとう
Yes, thank you.
引き止めてごめんなさい
My apologies for keeping you.
There's no mistake.
間違いない　その窃盗犯が今　この世界の神を演じているんだ
That burglar is playing the role of God in this world right now.
Using the PCs they've stolen, they're starting to tamper with the NPCs.
盗んだパソコンを使って　NPCたちに介入を初めているんだ
But how should I catch them?
けど　どうやってつかまえる
I don't have time to waste.
悠長なことはしていられない
The shadows are multiplying this very moment.
いまも影は増え続けてるのに
盗むと言っても簡単に運べるようなものじゃない
Well, it's easy to say "steal,"
but these aren't easily transportable.
夜に忍び込んで台車に乗せて外に持ち出している
Do they sneak in at night and carry them out on a dolly?
Or maybe out the window?
あるいは窓からか
あっ
見つけた
There you are.
え　ちょっ　まさか
What? No way...
Not the Guild again!
またギルトかよ
I've always walked this path alone; when I look back, everyone is so far away.
itsumo hitori de aruiteta furikaeru to minna ha tooku
いつもひとりで歩いてた　振り返るとみんなは遠く
Even so, I kept on walking. That was my strength.
soredemo atashi ha aruita sore ga tsuyosa datta
それでもあたしは歩いた　それが強さだった
"Nothing frightens me any longer", I mumble softly.
mou nanimo kowakunai sou tsubuyaitemiseru
もう何も恐くない　そう呟いてみせる
Eventually, everyone ends up alone,
itsuka hito ha hitori ni natte
いつか人は一人になって
And is left with only their memories.
omoide no naka ni ikiteku dake
思い出の中に生きてくだけ
In order to appreciate even sorrow and continue smiling,
kodoku sae aishi waratterareru you ni
孤独さえ愛し笑ってられるように
I'll keep on fighting,
atashi ha tatakaunda
あたしは戦うんだ
I won't show you my tears.
namida nante misenainda
涙なんて見せないんだ
Next Episode Preview
We're going to break through!
Knockin' on heaven's door.
What is this world?
I thought even God would be surprised!
So the war's... going to end...
I don't think anyone'd notice even if you disappeared right now!
Get lost!
Disappear pitifully, just like toilet paper!
I only move when it helps Yurippe!
One hundred... Just think, we have reinforcements.
We'll be a band next time, too!
I am amazed you made it this far.
Reach out!
If I disappear from this place... can I redo my life?